翻译：@隐秀_（seriouszyx）
Now, I know you're just itching to build an array-based list, and we will soon.
我知道你渴望构建一个基于数组的链表，快了
But before we do that, just for the sake of really good scholarship, let's compare and contrast arrays and classes.
但在这之前，为了真正的学术研究，让我们来对比一下数组和类
So when it comes to implementing a data structure,
涉及到实现数据结构时
say a list or a set or a map or any other number of things,
比方说链表、集合、图或任何东西
both arrays and classes can be used to organize a bunch of memory boxes.
数组和类都可以用来组织内存盒子
Now, they have different flavors.
它们稍有不同
So for example, the planet class, we have a bunch of named fields.
例如 Planet 类，我们有一堆命名的字段
And for example, here I've constructed a planet earth that has a string name and a double mass.
例如我在这里构建了一个地球，它有一个 String 的 name 和一个 double 的 mass
By contrast, arrays, as we've noted, are a set of numbered,
相反，数组是一组编号的集合
or a sequence of numbered, memory boxes.
或一系列编号的内存盒子
Now, for arrays, they have to be all the same type.
对于数组，它们必须都是同一类型
And if we want to access them, we use bracket notation.
可以使用方括号表示法访问它们
And classes, they could be all different types.
类可能包含不同类型
And we access them using dot notation.
使用点表示法访问它们
In both cases, though, we have a fixed number of memory boxes.
不过这两种情况下，我们都有固定数量的内存盒子
That can never change, at least in the Java language.
这一点永远不会改变，至少在 Java 中是这样
Other languages may be more permissive.
其他语言可能更为宽松
So let's imagine what's really different about that.
让我们想象一下到底有什么不同之处
What, philosophically, is really important here?
从哲学上讲，这里真正重要的是什么？
Well, one really big difference is that with arrays, we can actually compute the indices we want at runtime.
一个真正大的区别是，对于数组，我们实际上可以在运行时计算我们想要的索引
So imagine the following.
想象一下以下情况
We construct an integer array, like so,
我们构造一个整型数组
and then we ask our user, what index do you want?
然后问我们的用户，你想要什么索引？
So we try running this program, which I'm not going to do live,
试着运行这个程序，我不会直播运行
but it would say, what index do you want?
它会说，你想要什么索引？
And we compile and run this program,
我们编译并运行这个程序
and maybe we type in two.
比如输入2
So now we have this index of interest, two,
也就是我们有了感兴趣的索引2
that was not known at compile time,
这在编译时是未知的
and then we can say, hey, give me back item number two from this array.
我们可以说，把这个数组中的第2项给我
And when we print it out, we'll get 102.
打印会得到102
By contrast, with classes, we cannot compute those at runtime.
相比之下，对于类，我们不能在运行时计算它们
So for example, suppose we have a field of interest, mass,
假设我们对 mass 感兴趣
and then we actually try to get back that field of interest.
然后获取感兴趣的字段
So in this case, rather than asking the user,
这种情况中，没有问用户
I'm just having the string hard-coded in here into this field.
而是将字符串硬编码到这个字段中
And in this case, what happens when we try to do earth fieldOfInterest, the compiler says no.
在这种情况下，执行 Earth[fieldOfInterest]，编译器拒绝了
You cannot say earth fieldOfInterest.
不可以用 fieldOfInterest
That is forbidden.
这是被禁止的
The reason is that's just how Java works.
原因是 Java 就是这样工作的
You cannot throw in a particular field you want and get it back.
你不能抛出想要的特定字段，然后再将其取回
That's just how the language is designed.
语言就是这样设计的
It will say array required, but instead a planet was found.
会报错：“需要数组，却发现了 planet”
Now, you might try and say, I'm going to be extra clever.
你可能会这样尝试，更聪明些
What I'm going to do is I'm going to use dot notation, because I know that's what's supposed to happen with classes.
你将使用点表示法，因为这是类应该发生的事情
But in this case, when I say earth.fieldOfInterest,
但此时，执行 earth.fieldOfInterest
then I will get, I don't know what you mean.
会得到：“我不明白你的意思”
I tried to find something called fieldOfInterest
试着找一个叫 FieldOfInterest 的东西
that's part of the planet class, but as you note, I have mass.
它是 Planet 类的一部分，但我有 mass
I have name.
我有 name
I do not have fieldOfInterest.
我没有 fieldOfInterest
So in Java, you just can't do that.
因此在 Java 中不能这样做
Now, I'm kind of lying, because there is technically a way of doing that.
其实我在撒谎，因为严格来说，有一种方法可以做到这一点
And if you want, you can click this link and learn all about something called the reflections API,
如果你愿意，可以单击此链接，了解有关反射 API 的所有信息
but it's not something that's considered good style.
但这种风格不被认为是好的
So ultimately, in Java, when you're using a class,
所以在 Java 中，当你使用一个类时
the only easy way to access a member of a class is with what I'll call hard-coded dot notation.
访问类成员的唯一简单方法是使用硬编码点表示法
So for example, if I want to get back mass,
举个例子，如果我想获得 mass
I can only do it by saying p.mass.
只可以使用 p.mass
I can't do p.fieldOfInterest or p braces fieldOfInterest.
不能使用 p.fieldOfInterest 或 p[fieldOfInterest]
It won't work.
不行
And so the Java compiler-- ultimately,
所以 Java 编译器
the idea here is it doesn't treat something on either side of a dot as an expression.
它不把点两边的东西当作表达式
It won't actually evaluate this thing.
它实际上不会评估这个东西
And thus it won't work.
所以没用
And if you're curious about these kind of philosophical issues, like if you're kind of--
如果你对这类哲学问题很好奇
if you're the kind of person who looks at this and says,
如果你是那种看着这个就会说
there's something deep here and something cool,
“这里有一些很深奥很炫酷的东西”
I encourage you to later take a compilers or a programming languages course,
我鼓励你以后参加编译器或编程语言课程
which will really go into the philosophy of these things in more depth.
将会真正深入到这些东西的哲学中
Now, it is possible--
现在
I'll just make a quick note, though--
我还是做个简短的说明
you can do funny things if you really want.
如果真的想，你可以做一些有趣的事情
And the reason that Java doesn't let you do this, just to mention this philosophically,
Java 不允许你这样做的原因，从哲学上讲
is that it keeps our code simple.
是为了保持代码简单
Reflection leads to ugly code, strange code.
反射会导致难看的代码、奇怪的代码
If Java actually let you do this,
如果 Java 确实允许你这样做
it would cause a lot of headaches.
这会很头疼
And so the Java designer said no,
所以 Java 设计者拒绝了
and they decided, well, if you really want,
他们决定，如果你实在想
you can use the reflections API.
可以使用反射 API
But everybody knows-- I know, you now know--
但是每个人都知道，我知道，你知道
that using reflection for this kind of purpose is just considered terrible style.
将反射用于这种目的被认为是糟糕的风格
And the reason is simply that with big programs,
原因很简单，就是在大型项目中
it's just an extra thing you have to think about.
这是需要你额外考虑的事情
So the language was built to restrict the choices you could make,
语言就是用来限制你可以做出的选择的
which, again, is one of the strongest arguments in the favor of Java.
这也是支持 Java 的最有力的论据之一
All right. That's it.
好的
So end of these set of videos.
这组视频结束了
Next, we'll start building an array-based list,
接下来将开始构建基于数组的链表
翻译：@隐秀_（seriouszyx）
and I hope you liked the philosophy.
我希望你喜欢这里的哲学